<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>VMware Explore on Intellegence Modifer</title>
        <link>https://intelligencemodifier.com/tags/vmware-explore/</link>
        <description>Recent content in VMware Explore on Intellegence Modifer</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://intelligencemodifier.com/tags/vmware-explore/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>VMware Explore 2024 Las Vegas Content Catalog is Live!</title>
        <link>https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/vmware-explore-2024-lasvegas-content-catalog-live/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/vmware-explore-2024-lasvegas-content-catalog-live/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/vmware-explore-2024-lasvegas-content-catalog-live/vmwx24.png" alt="Featured image of post VMware Explore 2024 Las Vegas Content Catalog is Live!" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;With this year&amp;rsquo;s VMware Explore Las Vegas drawing nearer, the opening of the Content Catalog is finally here. At the time of writing the catalog lists over four hundred sessions spread out across multiple session types, level and focuses. While you cannot build your scheduled yet, that is slated to open on July 16th. For now, you can go through and start to favorite sessions you want to attend. I would highly recommend starting to go through the catalog to give you ample time to browse and save yourself a lot of time when the scheduler opens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;start-using-the-catalog&#34;&gt;Start Using the Catalog
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you are already registered, you can just login and head straight to the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://r.vmwebapp.com/tr/cl/LwWrDwk5uK3F_FyvYUzRTamUMJgOhpP_vUp412LlBI8qd74bnDD31UcNM6i5WQMdG3q6LMlF0FxKojBvP0pnJ_K2dx59_K3Faes6x8R52Mw0lnqfvCCapXzK1BquKdRGecylcuteRvTPxQYbDkj4tqlw46ErqWPvt6Go39uMoYlxighrD1Lf6B4T1WXm8YxTTysSWvxMxlOap5p9gESRweT0aXSFEssvoaXpsp4CNuT1t2STKVLrXm3Yjzo4WtPCb-u9PhvICRTsELtV9dNMYR_2YDEV-R66OwsaZU_WuFeRFxOvKGqyVK5ggU2Lm5FFVacqnXyvlqqv0vajNNuJdgBfUql5J6cxE4Vpt_5CMNv_a4GLXZE8MEe14i3nMbbllAVMC8M4TZJqLFl9v9Fua8ujbQVhOy5_31_TgHSngHC1FhBvRy2Ol3qXwM4NcIlA&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Content Catalog&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If are not registered yet &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://r.vmwebapp.com/tr/cl/c28UAFluxaZrH0J_xTxVmBaKdRbN6jAxDWi84qPo3uthoiCC9PjFUMItn74EdHpz7hKcnJqJhoomeSD9wDjVSOl0-yhKw52OBAUXnN8hvSYr2sVj_IrC9wcT4tsamnswYYnbq-XR_s6xZ593jYUbvdLBAdj0wpO0mCfSD3wVC4cX1S15JYqpFQswq3spmVtC8fJ-5JGzBa0QKcS5nr1Uhf1MX5lKmiGO7NOejX_3oxkbEZtvgcZshW2VHEtKJoMx6xZOtuszOkUG9PF7gvKJ5Uz2eG3SiJjQf66yXTrDX_JIBGngQY4XrNY83nfbV7tHZKABXglA9l3cvQaxwlAmkFlKT9of0QwBHiN2_dpPE0HBNfChz60w7AS9BvcXzXdQY4A&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;make sure you do before July 15th for $200 off your pass&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start looking through sessions using the filters on the left.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you find a session, you will want to attend just click the &lt;img src=&#34;https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/vmware-explore-2024-lasvegas-content-catalog-live/cc-heart.png&#34;
	width=&#34;27&#34;
	height=&#34;20&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/vmware-explore-2024-lasvegas-content-catalog-live/cc-heart_hue60694d792c6caadbcb77dcd4d90f090_535_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/vmware-explore-2024-lasvegas-content-catalog-live/cc-heart_hue60694d792c6caadbcb77dcd4d90f090_535_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;135&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;324px&#34;
	
&gt; to add it to your favorites list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then when the scheduling opens, you can filter your list in one click using the &amp;lsquo;My Favorites&amp;rsquo; checkbox on the left and start to fill out your schedule. In case you want a starting point for your search, I have put together a few predefined searches for the type of content I look for and enjoy. Firstly, my preference for any session is for it to be as technical as possible. So, this first search is all the technical level 200 and 300 sessions in the catalog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://event.vmware.com/flow/vmware/explore2024lv/content/page/catalog?search=&amp;amp;search.level=1517937137830003aCWu&amp;amp;search.level=1517937137830004asmP&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Technical Level 200/300 Sessions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, is a search for all sessions taking place on either the Community or {code} Theater stages. This is a fantastic way to learn about multiple topics quickly. Each talk is about half the length of a traditional Breakout Session, so they are also great for filling gaps in your schedule or just stopping by while you are in The Hub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://event.vmware.com/flow/vmware/explore2024lv/content/page/catalog?search=&amp;amp;search.sessiontype=15295276596790010ww1&amp;amp;search.sessiontype=1715716562081001Ygbv&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Community and {Code} Theater Sessions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and before I forget I am going to plug my own session this year! This will be my second time talking on the {code} stage but the first-time flying solo. If you are at all interested in how to manage your physical hosts via the REDFISH API here is my session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://event.vmware.com/flow/vmware/explore2024lv/content/page/catalog?search=1181&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Automating Building Your Hosts with REDFISH API [CODE1181LV]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, you need to make sure to have activities like the Expo Bash and end of conference party on your schedule. This search pulls up all Activity events taking place during the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://event.vmware.com/flow/vmware/explore2024lv/content/page/catalog?search=&amp;amp;search.sessiontype=1659883917381001FrF2&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Conference Activies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, this helps you get a start to picking out sessions, and I cannot wait for you to join us at VMware Explore 2024 on August 26th!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>VMware Explore 2024 is Right Around the Corner</title>
        <link>https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/vmware-explore-2024-is-right-around-the-corner/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/vmware-explore-2024-is-right-around-the-corner/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/vmware-explore-2024-is-right-around-the-corner/explore-2024-banner.png" alt="Featured image of post VMware Explore 2024 is Right Around the Corner" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is that time of year again, Summer is starting to show up, everyone is shocked half the year is over already, and VMware Explore is right around the corner. It has been quite a while since I last sat down to write a blog entry, and while quite a bit has changed for me both personally and professionally in 4 years, I still look forward to VMware Explore every year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I get too far, let me leave some important links to learn more about VMware Explore 2024, which takes place at The Venetian Convention and Expo Center in Las Vegas, August 26-29.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VMware Explore Official Site and Registration: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://shorturl.at/svCJM&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://shorturl.at/svCJM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VMware Explore LinkedIn Group: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/groups/2028037&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.linkedin.com/groups/2028037&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Convince your manager letter template: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.vmware.com/explore/us/attend/pricing&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.vmware.com/explore/us/attend/pricing&lt;/a&gt; (link near the top of the page)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/vmware-explore-2024-is-right-around-the-corner/explore-2024-value.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/vmware-explore-2024-is-right-around-the-corner/explore-2024-value_hu6af6490234a7eecab961e3735e159e44_342800_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/vmware-explore-2024-is-right-around-the-corner/explore-2024-value_hu6af6490234a7eecab961e3735e159e44_342800_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel that this year will be an especially interesting year to attend. With the acquisition of VMware by Broadcom being the start to about every IT worker&amp;rsquo;s year, all eyes will be on the keynote stage to get a look into what the future holds. While we can assume &amp;ldquo;AI&amp;rdquo; will be another big focus this year, and even though I have my guesses at what could be announced, the product announcements, while interesting, are only one reason VMware Explore is easily my favorite conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;community-community-community&#34;&gt;Community, Community, Community
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;My favorite part of VMware Explore is absolutely being able to meet up with other members of the community in person. Last year was my first year attending as a member of Tanzu Vanguard, which was an additional group of amazing people I got to meet for the first time, and that is on top of meeting up with fellow members of the vExpert program and of course from various VMUG chapters. This year will be the first year I will be attending as a VMUG Leader as well, so I am extremely excited to meet up with that group as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are attending for your first time or have been in the past but filled your scheduled back-to-back with sessions, I strongly recommend blocking off time and spend some time in The Hub or other parts of the convention center talking to your fellow attendees. Most sessions are recorded and can be watched after you get home from the conference, but you will only have the 4 days of Explore to talk and learn from others in attendance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;dont-sleep-on-the-hands-on-labs&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t Sleep on the Hands-on Labs
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yes, I know you can access the Hands-on Labs at home, and while I do not necessarily recommend spending all your time in the HoL area for that reason, there are plenty of reasons to check them out. I personally am hoping to see that the Odyssey Tournament is coming back for 2024. This is a Timed, Skill-based challenge where you compete directly against your peers for a chance to make it to the final round and compete for some awesome prizes. I got to take place in 2022 and 2024 made it to the final round both times, and even took home second place in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides Odyssey, there are self-paced, and instructor led labs with their own daily prize drawings if you remember to check in and follow the directions for the day. You can also get a tour of what it takes to run that many labs during the conference which is super interesting to see. There are also typically a variety of new HoL that release at Explore first before being available online. So, make sure to look up any product you may have thought about looking at and see what labs are available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;keynotes-and-sessions&#34;&gt;Keynotes and Sessions
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, you still should make time for checking out the Keynotes and Sessions. Personally, I find grabbing a giant beanbag in The Hub the perfect way to start the Day while watching the Keynote event. No matter how many things may be rumored before the conference VMware always has an ace up their sleeve to announce. For sessions, I try to find sessions at least &amp;lsquo;Technical 200&amp;rsquo; or higher for things I am less experienced with and/or are likely to have an unfamiliar perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of my favorite session types are the Community Theater and {code} sessions that typically take place in or near The Hub. These are typically faster sessions on extremely focused topics and often will dive very deep into their topic (well as deep as the time limit allows). I even got to check another first off, my list last year when I gave my first {code} sessions talk along with fellow VMUG leader and former co-worker Russ Hamker. It was a nerve-racking experience leading up to and during the talk but once it was over, I knew I needed to find a topic for 2024. As it turns out, another talk of mine was accepted for the {code} sessions this year, so keep an eye on the Content Catalog for the When and Where.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;recharge-your-professional-batteries&#34;&gt;Recharge Your Professional Batteries
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a VERY introverted person, it caught me off guard when I attended my first VMworld in 2017 and despite the crowds of people I felt re-energized from spending those few days among like-minded people and learning about new and upcoming technologies. I soon realized that everyone just needs to be able to step away from the normal day to day of their job and get some motivation and innovative ideas to bring back with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;see-you-there&#34;&gt;See You There
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;If any of that sounds interesting to you, talk to your manager about going and what benefits it would have for you and what you could bring back to help the team. Just remember, Early Bird pricing ends on June 11th so the earlier you register the less the total cost you will need reimbursed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and almost forgot&amp;hellip; the vendor run parties and meals you can find and sign up for are a wonderful way to unwind once the conference ends each day. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
