<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>vmworld on </title>
    <link>https://IntModifier.github.io/tags/vmworld/</link>
    <description>Recent content in vmworld on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://IntModifier.github.io/tags/vmworld/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2019 - K is for Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://IntModifier.github.io/posts/2019/vmworld_2019_k_is_for_kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://IntModifier.github.io/posts/2019/vmworld_2019_k_is_for_kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>“Any Application, Any Cloud, Any Device” This was once again the main driving message behind all of VMworld this year. However, you could sum up a large majority of the event with one word, Kubernetes. VMware seemed to have something new related to what they refer to as ‘Cloud Native Applications’ everywhere you looked, I have tried to summarize some of the large announcements below.
Bitnami, Pivotal and Heptio VMware hasn’t been shy about acquisitions this past year, and several of them are directly related to enhancing their Cloud Native portfolio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vRealize at VMworld US 2019</title>
      <link>https://IntModifier.github.io/posts/2019/vrealize_at_vmworld_us_2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://IntModifier.github.io/posts/2019/vrealize_at_vmworld_us_2019/</guid>
      <description>It is that time of year again, with each VMworld we get new announcements for the vRealize Suite Cloud Management tools. This year, there is a common thread across most of them, supporting more Public Clouds and Kubernetes support, but if you listed to this year’s keynote that will likely not come as a surprise. We are also getting some pretty big updates in a few of the products as well, especially in the area of vRealize Automation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing vRealize Operations 8.0</title>
      <link>https://IntModifier.github.io/posts/2019/announcing_vrealize_operations_80/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://IntModifier.github.io/posts/2019/announcing_vrealize_operations_80/</guid>
      <description>Today during VMworld 2019, the next version of vRealize Operations Manager was announced. Version 8.0 focuses on improving many existing features and adding several new features especially in the area of Hybrid and Multi Cloud support. Here are some highlights of the new features you can expect when vRealize Operations Manager 8.0 drops later this year
Core Platform Updates  More powerful Self-Driving operations leveraging Machine Learning More What-If Analysis Scenarios including Hyper Converged Infrastructure and Data-center Comparison Troubleshooting Workbench – Correlate information in one dashboard to help track down root cause of issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing for VMworld 2019</title>
      <link>https://IntModifier.github.io/posts/2019/preparing_for_vmworld_2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://IntModifier.github.io/posts/2019/preparing_for_vmworld_2019/</guid>
      <description>I am very excited and honored to be selected to attend VMworld 2019 in San Francisco via the vExpert Blogger Pass. This will be my second VMworld, the first being in Vegas during 2017. So now that my travel plan is locked in, and I am scrolling through sessions to attend I wanted to look back at how I am planning my 2nd venture to this convention.
Keynotes I am of course planning to attend the Monday and Tuesday keynotes (at the time of writing I don’t see a end of conference keynote listed in the schedule).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMWorld 2018 - vRealize Suite Announcements</title>
      <link>https://IntModifier.github.io/posts/2018/vmworld_2018_vrealize_suite_announcements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://IntModifier.github.io/posts/2018/vmworld_2018_vrealize_suite_announcements/</guid>
      <description>I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to make it VMWorld this year, but I spent a good part of the day pouring over twitter and blog posts to find information on the 2018 version of the vRealize Suite. Below are just some quick notes on the features i am most excited about or found the most interesting, along with the official vmWare blog post link to learn more.
vRealize Automation - 7.5 (also vRealize Business for Cloud 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set-Location $VMworld2017</title>
      <link>https://IntModifier.github.io/posts/2017/set-location-vmworld2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://IntModifier.github.io/posts/2017/set-location-vmworld2017/</guid>
      <description>Well technically I am now back home, but I liked the title and ran with it.
This year, I was lucky enough to attend my first VMWorld in Las Vegas, NV. To say that it was awesome, would be an understatement. Not only did I have a chance listen to some amazing sessions (and ear mark several for viewing once the VoDs are up), but I also got to meet quite a few VMware Community members.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
