<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Intellegence Modifer</title>
        <link>https://intelligencemodifier.com/post/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Intellegence Modifer</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://intelligencemodifier.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>VMware Explore 2024 Las Vegas Content Catalog is Live!</title>
        <link>https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/vmware-explore-2024-lasvegas-content-catalog-live/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/vmware-explore-2024-lasvegas-content-catalog-live/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/vmware-explore-2024-lasvegas-content-catalog-live/vmwx24.png" alt="Featured image of post VMware Explore 2024 Las Vegas Content Catalog is Live!" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;With this year&amp;rsquo;s VMware Explore Las Vegas drawing nearer, the opening of the Content Catalog is finally here. At the time of writing the catalog lists over four hundred sessions spread out across multiple session types, level and focuses. While you cannot build your scheduled yet, that is slated to open on July 16th. For now, you can go through and start to favorite sessions you want to attend. I would highly recommend starting to go through the catalog to give you ample time to browse and save yourself a lot of time when the scheduler opens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;start-using-the-catalog&#34;&gt;Start Using the Catalog
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you are already registered, you can just login and head straight to the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://r.vmwebapp.com/tr/cl/LwWrDwk5uK3F_FyvYUzRTamUMJgOhpP_vUp412LlBI8qd74bnDD31UcNM6i5WQMdG3q6LMlF0FxKojBvP0pnJ_K2dx59_K3Faes6x8R52Mw0lnqfvCCapXzK1BquKdRGecylcuteRvTPxQYbDkj4tqlw46ErqWPvt6Go39uMoYlxighrD1Lf6B4T1WXm8YxTTysSWvxMxlOap5p9gESRweT0aXSFEssvoaXpsp4CNuT1t2STKVLrXm3Yjzo4WtPCb-u9PhvICRTsELtV9dNMYR_2YDEV-R66OwsaZU_WuFeRFxOvKGqyVK5ggU2Lm5FFVacqnXyvlqqv0vajNNuJdgBfUql5J6cxE4Vpt_5CMNv_a4GLXZE8MEe14i3nMbbllAVMC8M4TZJqLFl9v9Fua8ujbQVhOy5_31_TgHSngHC1FhBvRy2Ol3qXwM4NcIlA&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Content Catalog&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If are not registered yet &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://r.vmwebapp.com/tr/cl/c28UAFluxaZrH0J_xTxVmBaKdRbN6jAxDWi84qPo3uthoiCC9PjFUMItn74EdHpz7hKcnJqJhoomeSD9wDjVSOl0-yhKw52OBAUXnN8hvSYr2sVj_IrC9wcT4tsamnswYYnbq-XR_s6xZ593jYUbvdLBAdj0wpO0mCfSD3wVC4cX1S15JYqpFQswq3spmVtC8fJ-5JGzBa0QKcS5nr1Uhf1MX5lKmiGO7NOejX_3oxkbEZtvgcZshW2VHEtKJoMx6xZOtuszOkUG9PF7gvKJ5Uz2eG3SiJjQf66yXTrDX_JIBGngQY4XrNY83nfbV7tHZKABXglA9l3cvQaxwlAmkFlKT9of0QwBHiN2_dpPE0HBNfChz60w7AS9BvcXzXdQY4A&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;make sure you do before July 15th for $200 off your pass&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start looking through sessions using the filters on the left.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you find a session, you will want to attend just click the &lt;img src=&#34;https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/vmware-explore-2024-lasvegas-content-catalog-live/cc-heart.png&#34;
	width=&#34;27&#34;
	height=&#34;20&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/vmware-explore-2024-lasvegas-content-catalog-live/cc-heart_hue60694d792c6caadbcb77dcd4d90f090_535_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/vmware-explore-2024-lasvegas-content-catalog-live/cc-heart_hue60694d792c6caadbcb77dcd4d90f090_535_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;135&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;324px&#34;
	
&gt; to add it to your favorites list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then when the scheduling opens, you can filter your list in one click using the &amp;lsquo;My Favorites&amp;rsquo; checkbox on the left and start to fill out your schedule. In case you want a starting point for your search, I have put together a few predefined searches for the type of content I look for and enjoy. Firstly, my preference for any session is for it to be as technical as possible. So, this first search is all the technical level 200 and 300 sessions in the catalog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://event.vmware.com/flow/vmware/explore2024lv/content/page/catalog?search=&amp;amp;search.level=1517937137830003aCWu&amp;amp;search.level=1517937137830004asmP&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Technical Level 200/300 Sessions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, is a search for all sessions taking place on either the Community or {code} Theater stages. This is a fantastic way to learn about multiple topics quickly. Each talk is about half the length of a traditional Breakout Session, so they are also great for filling gaps in your schedule or just stopping by while you are in The Hub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://event.vmware.com/flow/vmware/explore2024lv/content/page/catalog?search=&amp;amp;search.sessiontype=15295276596790010ww1&amp;amp;search.sessiontype=1715716562081001Ygbv&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Community and {Code} Theater Sessions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and before I forget I am going to plug my own session this year! This will be my second time talking on the {code} stage but the first-time flying solo. If you are at all interested in how to manage your physical hosts via the REDFISH API here is my session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://event.vmware.com/flow/vmware/explore2024lv/content/page/catalog?search=1181&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Automating Building Your Hosts with REDFISH API [CODE1181LV]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, you need to make sure to have activities like the Expo Bash and end of conference party on your schedule. This search pulls up all Activity events taking place during the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://event.vmware.com/flow/vmware/explore2024lv/content/page/catalog?search=&amp;amp;search.sessiontype=1659883917381001FrF2&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Conference Activies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, this helps you get a start to picking out sessions, and I cannot wait for you to join us at VMware Explore 2024 on August 26th!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>VMware Explore 2024 is Right Around the Corner</title>
        <link>https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/vmware-explore-2024-is-right-around-the-corner/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/vmware-explore-2024-is-right-around-the-corner/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/vmware-explore-2024-is-right-around-the-corner/explore-2024-banner.png" alt="Featured image of post VMware Explore 2024 is Right Around the Corner" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is that time of year again, Summer is starting to show up, everyone is shocked half the year is over already, and VMware Explore is right around the corner. It has been quite a while since I last sat down to write a blog entry, and while quite a bit has changed for me both personally and professionally in 4 years, I still look forward to VMware Explore every year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I get too far, let me leave some important links to learn more about VMware Explore 2024, which takes place at The Venetian Convention and Expo Center in Las Vegas, August 26-29.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VMware Explore Official Site and Registration: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://shorturl.at/svCJM&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://shorturl.at/svCJM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VMware Explore LinkedIn Group: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/groups/2028037&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.linkedin.com/groups/2028037&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Convince your manager letter template: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.vmware.com/explore/us/attend/pricing&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.vmware.com/explore/us/attend/pricing&lt;/a&gt; (link near the top of the page)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/vmware-explore-2024-is-right-around-the-corner/explore-2024-value.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/vmware-explore-2024-is-right-around-the-corner/explore-2024-value_hu6af6490234a7eecab961e3735e159e44_342800_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/vmware-explore-2024-is-right-around-the-corner/explore-2024-value_hu6af6490234a7eecab961e3735e159e44_342800_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel that this year will be an especially interesting year to attend. With the acquisition of VMware by Broadcom being the start to about every IT worker&amp;rsquo;s year, all eyes will be on the keynote stage to get a look into what the future holds. While we can assume &amp;ldquo;AI&amp;rdquo; will be another big focus this year, and even though I have my guesses at what could be announced, the product announcements, while interesting, are only one reason VMware Explore is easily my favorite conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;community-community-community&#34;&gt;Community, Community, Community
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;My favorite part of VMware Explore is absolutely being able to meet up with other members of the community in person. Last year was my first year attending as a member of Tanzu Vanguard, which was an additional group of amazing people I got to meet for the first time, and that is on top of meeting up with fellow members of the vExpert program and of course from various VMUG chapters. This year will be the first year I will be attending as a VMUG Leader as well, so I am extremely excited to meet up with that group as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are attending for your first time or have been in the past but filled your scheduled back-to-back with sessions, I strongly recommend blocking off time and spend some time in The Hub or other parts of the convention center talking to your fellow attendees. Most sessions are recorded and can be watched after you get home from the conference, but you will only have the 4 days of Explore to talk and learn from others in attendance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;dont-sleep-on-the-hands-on-labs&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t Sleep on the Hands-on Labs
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yes, I know you can access the Hands-on Labs at home, and while I do not necessarily recommend spending all your time in the HoL area for that reason, there are plenty of reasons to check them out. I personally am hoping to see that the Odyssey Tournament is coming back for 2024. This is a Timed, Skill-based challenge where you compete directly against your peers for a chance to make it to the final round and compete for some awesome prizes. I got to take place in 2022 and 2024 made it to the final round both times, and even took home second place in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides Odyssey, there are self-paced, and instructor led labs with their own daily prize drawings if you remember to check in and follow the directions for the day. You can also get a tour of what it takes to run that many labs during the conference which is super interesting to see. There are also typically a variety of new HoL that release at Explore first before being available online. So, make sure to look up any product you may have thought about looking at and see what labs are available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;keynotes-and-sessions&#34;&gt;Keynotes and Sessions
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, you still should make time for checking out the Keynotes and Sessions. Personally, I find grabbing a giant beanbag in The Hub the perfect way to start the Day while watching the Keynote event. No matter how many things may be rumored before the conference VMware always has an ace up their sleeve to announce. For sessions, I try to find sessions at least &amp;lsquo;Technical 200&amp;rsquo; or higher for things I am less experienced with and/or are likely to have an unfamiliar perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of my favorite session types are the Community Theater and {code} sessions that typically take place in or near The Hub. These are typically faster sessions on extremely focused topics and often will dive very deep into their topic (well as deep as the time limit allows). I even got to check another first off, my list last year when I gave my first {code} sessions talk along with fellow VMUG leader and former co-worker Russ Hamker. It was a nerve-racking experience leading up to and during the talk but once it was over, I knew I needed to find a topic for 2024. As it turns out, another talk of mine was accepted for the {code} sessions this year, so keep an eye on the Content Catalog for the When and Where.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;recharge-your-professional-batteries&#34;&gt;Recharge Your Professional Batteries
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a VERY introverted person, it caught me off guard when I attended my first VMworld in 2017 and despite the crowds of people I felt re-energized from spending those few days among like-minded people and learning about new and upcoming technologies. I soon realized that everyone just needs to be able to step away from the normal day to day of their job and get some motivation and innovative ideas to bring back with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;see-you-there&#34;&gt;See You There
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;If any of that sounds interesting to you, talk to your manager about going and what benefits it would have for you and what you could bring back to help the team. Just remember, Early Bird pricing ends on June 11th so the earlier you register the less the total cost you will need reimbursed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and almost forgot&amp;hellip; the vendor run parties and meals you can find and sign up for are a wonderful way to unwind once the conference ends each day. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>SCCM Patching Kickstart Script</title>
        <link>https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/sccm-patching-kickstart-script/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/sccm-patching-kickstart-script/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;solving-problems&#34;&gt;Solving Problems
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A while back I had the need at my day job to help stream line our Windows Server patching process.  We had moved to using SCCM and Maintenance Windows but due to business requirements were not able to allow software updates to be installed too far ahead of time and just sit at PENDING REBOOT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, SCCM  doesn’t really give you a lot of room for fine tuning, and none of the out of box options fit all our requirements. So My coworkers and I started look at various options to get around this.  After several attempts we settled on a “kick-start” script and scheduled task to be installed on needed systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code can be found on my &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/IntModifier/PowerShell/tree/master/sccm_software_update_kickstart&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;quick-run-down&#34;&gt;Quick Run Down
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We installed the script and a scheduled task to run it over and over on the needed systems using SCCM itself. Once installed, the script runs as SYSTEM every hour and starts to check the WMI name space on the local system for any registered maintenance windows. The script currently look for any MWs coming up between 4 and 2 hours away. Once it gets within 4 hours of the next MW, it then queries the SCCM Software Center for all pending updates and then triggers the installs to start (all through WMI again).  Once it triggers patching it writes an event to the Event Log letting you know when it started patches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As long as you have reboots blocked by your Patching/Maintenance Window rules you should be all set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The script isn’t perfect but it was able to shave hours off outage time in some cases for us, so I wanted to put this out publicly in case it can help anyone else trim down working on the weekends.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Domain Services with Zentyal OS</title>
        <link>https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/domain-services-with-zentyalos/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/domain-services-with-zentyalos/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;While building out the new Intmod NUC lab, I needed to decide on how I was going to handle typical Domain services for it. I just need a basic setup to allow me to properly setup my vSphere lab. The first route of course would be spinning up a Windows domain controller and all the fixins; either by using the trial ISOs and having to rebuild  the domain every 180 days or so, or by shelling out the cash for a license. I really didn’t like either option for my current needs.  1 could be solved by spending time to write some PorwerShell build scripts and the other was just additional money  I didn’t want to spend right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/domain-services-with-zentyalos/zentyal.png&#34;
	width=&#34;376&#34;
	height=&#34;106&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/domain-services-with-zentyalos/zentyal_hu30905a3bad6e7ca72555fa354a66fe35_2710_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/domain-services-with-zentyalos/zentyal_hu30905a3bad6e7ca72555fa354a66fe35_2710_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;354&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;851px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While i was deciding which route to go with I remembered coming across a Linux distribution a few years ago that was designed to be an alternative to Windows domain controllers.  After some searching around I re-found  Zentryal (specifically the Development Edition which is free to use). Based off of Ubuntu Server 18.04.4 LTS,  Zentyal can serve as your domain controller, mail server, certificate authority and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;setup&#34;&gt;Setup
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Getting it installed was pretty straight forward, the only catch being that the “Easy Installer” in Workstation for Ubuntu doesn’t play nice with the Zentyal installer. After getting passed that and using the default options for install, I was presented with a guided wizard that walked me through picking server roles and configuring them.  For my lab setup i just needed the basics so i setup:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Directory Services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DNS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Certificate Authority&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the Zentyal setup then auto selected a few other roles that were dependencies of what i selected, and ran through installing and configuring each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/domain-services-with-zentyalos/zentyal_setup.png&#34;
	width=&#34;469&#34;
	height=&#34;525&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/domain-services-with-zentyalos/zentyal_setup_hu903433b52a61e91ad1dcbe9887abd028_25374_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/domain-services-with-zentyalos/zentyal_setup_hu903433b52a61e91ad1dcbe9887abd028_25374_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;89&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;214px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;usage&#34;&gt;Usage
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once Zentyal is setup, you no longer have to access the VM and can access all the functions of the server via its web console. The UI is for the most part usable. There are a few things that I would like to see cleaner but it gets the job done. There is a bit of a learning curve to the web console that I still miss from time to time. Most (but not all ) times you make a change, you need to remember to click SAVE in the upper right hand side Until you do the changes won’t be active and will just site pending on the server.  This gets me the most when setting up DNS entries, probably because you already click OK a few times as part of the process but nothing counts unless you click SAVE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/domain-services-with-zentyalos/zentyal_dash.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1000&#34;
	height=&#34;313&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/domain-services-with-zentyalos/zentyal_dash_hu10d9b05ca9fdbb9ce624d4edffd83aa9_53329_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/domain-services-with-zentyalos/zentyal_dash_hu10d9b05ca9fdbb9ce624d4edffd83aa9_53329_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;319&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;766px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating users accounts, groups, DNS entries, and certificates are all pretty straight forward. However users looking for more then just the basics may not be satisfied. Things like managed service accounts, or uploading CSRs for certificates requests do not currently exist to my knowledge. Not a big deal for a lab but I’m sure their are some out there that would want these. I honestly can’t day anything for the DNS/Firewall/Networking components, I have only setup a few DNS records for my lab so far and all the other defaults work for me currently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One bit I have yet to be setup is having more then one domain controller.  When I build the 2nd and try to join the existing domain the join fails.  This could just take some more tinkering and learning on my part but it doesn’t seem to be as straight forward as I thought it would be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the time being Zentyal is exactly what I wanted for my home lab, a non-expiring, simple to setup, server that hosts the basic domain services i need to setup my vSphere lab. However, my I do want my home lab to be a learning platform for  I would come across in an Enterprise settings. So eventually I probably will replace the Zentyal OS with Microsoft domain controllers (or even just Azure AD) but for now I can give a recommendation to anyone looking for a quick and dirty domain setup for small to medium labs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Blogtober 2020 &#43; Homelab</title>
        <link>https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/blogtober2020-homelab/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/blogtober2020-homelab/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;2020 has been a weird year to say the least, with several ups and downs. Like so many others, thanks to quarantine I found myself with even more time to myself at home then I already spent. Early on I told myself that i wanted to get X and Y done, do more of Z, etc. etc.  but nearly 7 months in I have found it very hard to accomplish much.  More recently I have started to find the motivation to push myself more and more and I am excited to share 2 small bits that I am working on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;blogtober-2020&#34;&gt;Blogtober 2020
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I want to blog more. I started this blog over 5 years ago, and have yet to find any sort of cadence I can hold myself to. So, when I saw Matt Heldstab (@mattheldstab) sending out this call for Blogtober during this year’s VMworld I decided I wanted to attempt to hold myself to the 5 posts during the month of October.  So I started on this post and ideas for the other 4. Fingers crossed I manage to hit ‘Publish’ on all of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;intmodlab-10&#34;&gt;Intmod.lab 1.0
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Earlier on this year, I also decided I wanted to finally setup a lab in which I can work on improving my technical skill sets. Past attempts at this never quite got where I wanted them to and my main limitation being an apartment dweller was always the space that some 2nd (or 3rd) hand servers would take up. So when i saw William Lam from virtuallyGhetto posting about the 10th Gen i7 NUCs and saw they got up to 6 core/12 thread now, I knew I had found a solution that could work.  So over a few months I gathered up:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 x Intel NUC10i7FNH&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6 x 32gb Samsung SODIMM memory&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 x 2TB Crucial MX500 SATA SSD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 x 500GB Samsung 970 EVO NVME SSD (after finding out the Crucial P2 ones don’&amp;rsquo;t yet play nice with ESXi)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 x Vantec USB 3.0 Dual Gigabit USB Network Adapter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once i got the first NUC with its needed bits in, I set to work learning how to setup ESXi with the extra needed custom installs needed to handle the 10th Gen NUCs built in NIC and the USB one as well.  After a few weekends of attempts and reading blogs i manged to get it setup correctly and later on in the summer had all 3 up and going in a VSAN clusters. (with a few re-builds needed along the way). I am also trying to use Zentyal OS as my domain services server instead of using a trial copy of Windows Server that needs regular rebuilding. My hope is that a few entries for this years Blogtober will be on the next steps I take with this lab, to help me push towards both my goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>vExpert 2020 - 2nd Half Applications Are Open. You Should Apply</title>
        <link>https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/vexpert2020-2nd-half-applications-open/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/vexpert2020-2nd-half-applications-open/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;First - if you know you want to apply to the VMware vExpert program go here: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://vexpert.vmware.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://vexpert.vmware.com/&lt;/a&gt;  You only have until June 20th before applications close again - Don’t Delay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you may be unsure if you should apply, not feel confident you will make it, or just want more information about the program before applying; Keep reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-the-vmware-vexpert-program&#34;&gt;What is the VMware vExpert Program?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quoted from the front page of the vExpert site:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The VMware vExpert program is VMware&amp;rsquo;s global evangelism and advocacy  program. The program is designed to put VMware&amp;rsquo;s marketing resources  towards your &amp;gt; advocacy efforts. Promotion of your articles, exposure at  our global events, co-op advertising, traffic analysis, and early access  to beta programs and &amp;gt; VMware&amp;rsquo;s roadmap. The awards are for individuals,  not companies, and last for one year. Employees of both customers and  partners can receive the awards…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what does that mean for you? Simply put this is VMware’s global customer (and partner) advocacy program. Meaning if you love working with, teaching, or just discussing VMware solutions this group is probably for you, but even if you are newer to the VMware community, you should give it some thought.  When you awarded membership, it is for one year (If you join in the 2nd round of applications like are open now your year still ‘expires’ at the same time those that join the program during the 1st round) and is awarded to you, not the company you work for so even if you change jobs during that year you are still a member.  Every vExpert re-applies every year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The program consists of the general vExpert group and then also has a list of sub-programs dedicated to a particular collection of VMware solutions. These sub-programs are run by the internal business groups at VMware, so you really get connected to the people behind the products. As of this year there are 7 sub programs, 6 of those are focused on certain solution stacks and they are, NSX, EUC, HCX, Cloud Management, Security, and Cloud Provider. The 7th group is a dedicated group of vExpert members called vExpert Pro, who help spreading the word about the program and act as mentors within the program, especially to those joining for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most Importantly - the vExpert program is a place where you can share and gain knowledge from like-minded professionals globally It’s like having access to VIP room of the VMware and VMUG communities that is even more hyper focused on sharing knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-can-join-the-vexpert-program&#34;&gt;Who can join the vExpert program?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Probably You. Seriously though, vExpert members come from all aspects of IT life. Customers, Partners and even VMware employees of all experience levels are eligible. The only real two requirements that I know of are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apply - You can’t get in if you don’t apply to get in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be active in the VMware community - We have Bloggers, podcasters,  a lot of Twitter users, YouTube video makers and more. All contributing to the #vCommunity in their own way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-the-vexpert-program-is-not&#34;&gt;What the vExpert Program is not
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A certification - this program is not a certification of any time. The VCA, VCP, VCAP, VCDX certifications are 100% a separate thing and the vExpert program doesn’t “fast track” or change any requirements for those. On the plus side, this means there are no tests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Sales Driven program focused on getting you to buy their products. As a matter of fact, you get quite the list of free stuff - more on that later&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A replacement for VMware Support - While most vExperts are willing to share their knowledge and answer questions they are not a part of the program to troubleshoot your environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A requirement to blog daily (or weekly) - You can look at this blog if you need proof, I am far from a regular blogger but I do find other ways to interact with the community as well. Everyone understands that everyone has day-jobs and other responsibilities and any ribbing you may get for not sharing in some way for a while is all in good fun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-you-get-out-of-it&#34;&gt;What you get out of it
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing you may have heard about is the free licensing for home lab user, and it’s true. With your membership to the program you get 1-year keys for use in YOUR home lab.  We don’t get ALL the software, but I’d say we get 99% of what people run in lab environments. Examples include vSphere, Workstation/Fusion, Horizon, vRealize Suite and many more. The only note I have is, there are only a few people running the vExpert program and they have to coordinate with many VMware teams to generate HUNDREDS of licenses at this point so please be patient. You likely won’t have them Day 1, but you will get them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are also quite a few other software vendors that have NFR/Lab licensing for vExperts, this list is ever changing so I’m not going to list any of the current vendors here. It will just be a surprise once you are in!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other big thing you get is less tangible but honestly could be even more beneficial - Access to network with an amazing group of knowledgeable people. My first year in the program I didn’t really have a functional lab to use any licensing - but this alone brought me back for year two (and three).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vCommunity is a unique online community. Full of people willing to help each other and share knowledge to anyone that asks. The vExpert program is kind of like getting into the VIP room for the community. Everyone had to apply meaning that they are all AT LEAST as interested in sharing and learning as you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To access this community, besides using #vExpert on twitter, you gain access to the vExpert Slack. Within the Slack there are many, many channels of various topics. Channels dedicated to products like vRA, sharing blog posts, and talking home labs to name a few.  Then if you eventually make it into one of the sub-programs like vExpert Cloud Management you can access to a private channel for you do talk with your fellow sub-program members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will also get access to attend a lot of vExpert only webinars. You will get product demos and technical dives from VMware employees and other vendors. These are technical reviews, not sales pitches. You may even get the chance to be a part of pre-release briefings for products designed to help you have your blog articles/videos/etc. ready for the embargo date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The program can also help get your content out to a wider audience. Not only can you share your content on the vExpert slack, but your public profile also contains a link to your website, and VMware may even share your blog out on one of the “blogs.vmware.com” sections. As an example, here is the latest ‘Blog Digest’ for the vExpert Cloud Management sub-program: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://t.co/ga0E2OnUex?amp=1&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://t.co/ga0E2OnUex?amp=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This last one is a bit up in the air this year with everything going on, some VMWorld related items&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Entrance into a dedicated vExpert party - a chance to unwind after a long day of sessions, meet people you may have only talked to virtually, and of course have fun. I sadly have not managed to make one of these since joining the vExpert group, but I understand Pat Gelsinger has even stopped by to meet the group in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some special SWAG from VMware and the vExpert team - a token of application for being there, and making this community what it is. Just remember to sign up ahead of time so they have the right amount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special SWAG from some vendors - Each year there are a handful vendors will have some special swag for vExperts, you may have to register ahead of time or it may just be first come, first serve but you will probably need to trade your contact information for like with all other swag; choose wisely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;em&gt;chance&lt;/em&gt; at a free full conference pass to VMWorld? Again not 100% sure since this year is a bit different, but yeah maybe. Each year (at least the past 2 years I have been in the program so far) the vExpert group gets a few “Blogger Passes” to VMWorld. Anyone in the vExpert program can apply, but you are expected to blog or share content in some way about your experience so keep that in mind. This also doesn’t cover travel to the conference so if you don’t think you (or your company) can spare the Hotel and Flight cost it would be kind to leave the applications to those that know they can make it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, you get out what you put into it. This group can be a huge source of information for you to further develop your career with. It’s not a certification, like I mentioned before, but think of it as self-training and improvement for your day job. Having the acceptance letter might not get you raise or fancy new title, but most employers, I would imagine, respond favorably when employees show they are willing to learn and improve themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;still-not-convinced-or-need-help-applying&#34;&gt;Still not convinced or need help applying?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Good News! There is a special vExpert Group just for this situation. The vExpert PRO group I mentioned before. Again, this group is made up of dedicated members for the vExpert community that want to help spread the word about this program. They go through a secondary application to join this group to show that they can help answer questions  you may have about joining. You can find the entire group either here: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://vexpert.vmware.com/directory/pro&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://vexpert.vmware.com/directory/pro&lt;/a&gt; or by hopping over to Twitter and either reaching out to @vExpertPro and/or using the #vExpertPro hashtag. Of course; you can also reach out to me at @vYooper on Twitter and I will do my best to answer your question or get you connected to someone that can.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>VMworld 2019 - K is for Kubernetes</title>
        <link>https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/vmworld-2019-kubernetes/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/vmworld-2019-kubernetes/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Any Application, Any Cloud, Any Device” This was once again the main driving message behind all of VMworld this year. However, you could sum up a large majority of the event with one word, Kubernetes. VMware seemed to have something new related to what they refer to as ‘Cloud Native Applications’ everywhere you looked, I have tried to summarize some of the large announcements below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bitnami-pivotal-and-heptio&#34;&gt;Bitnami, Pivotal and Heptio
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;VMware hasn’t been shy about acquisitions this past year, and several of them are directly related to enhancing their Cloud Native portfolio.  Last fall, VMware scooped up Heptio a start-up focused on professional services and supporting companies starting down the Kubernetes road. This evolved into the Essential PKS, a way for companies that need a more custom deployment for Kubernetes then what Enterprise PKS offers, while still being supported by VMware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jumping to spring 2019, VMware announced their acquisition of Bitnami. This addition adds specialty in the software packaging space, including of course containers. Already offering automation deployment of application stacks to AWS, Azure and Google Cloud Platform they quick slide right in line with VMware’s “Any Cloud” vision and not only could they enhance VMware’s container and Kubernetes products but possibly help re-work how VMware’s virtual appliances are built and deployed, much like the newly announced, self-contained, Kubernetes cluster based vRealize Automation 8.0 appliance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then a few days before VMworld, and then several times during the General Session(s), VMware announced their intention to acquire their partner in the PKS platform, Pivotal.  Enterprise PKS was VMware’s first large jump into production containers and Kubernetes. Not having any firsthand experience with PKS yet, I can only go off of what I have read but it seems that Enterprise PKS, while coming in at a premium over spinning up your own Kubernetes solution, it does a very nice job at delivering a close to Key-turn ready enterprise K8 deployment. If everything goes through and Pivotal joins the VMware fold, it will be interesting to see even tighter integration into the VMware stack can bring, especially when looking at the rest of the announcements this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-pacific&#34;&gt;Project Pacific
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next we get a peek into the future of vSphere, Project Pacific. To summarize in the style of a cereal slogan from the 90s, “You got your Kubernetes in my vSphere!” Pacific represents the effort to bring Kubernetes into your datacenter as a “first class citizen.” You will be able to see, interact, and manage your K8 Clusters right from the vSphere interface. This won’t just be an add-on for vSphere, the actual framework for Kubernetes will be weaved into the foundation of vSphere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now, I look at this a very good way to help any VMware customer (or future customer) bring “Cloud Native Applications” into their production environment. Also, VMware will be including their Harbor container registry as a part of this future version of vSphere. A seemingly small addition, but another step of lowering the barrier of entry into proper container and Kubernetes deployments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I will be the first to admit that my knowledge in Kubernetes is still at a point where I can’t do justice into some of the technical details on how VMware plans to make Kubernetes seamless with Project Pacific. However I can recommend that you check out the Technical Overview by Jared Rosoff  on the VMware blogs and his and Michael West’s VMworld session (HBI4500BU) up on VMworld Videos. You can also find the “Introducing Project Pacific” breakout session by Himanshu Singh and Kit Colbert (HBI4937BU) on the VMworld video site, along with checking out the Day 2 General Session for some live use case demos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tanzu-and-tanzu-mission-control&#34;&gt;Tanzu and Tanzu Mission Control
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another piece of the VMware Kubernetes puzzle was also announced, VMware Tanzu and  Tanzu Mission Control. Where Pacific focuses on helping you run and manage Kubernetes within vSphere, Tanzu’s focus is you with Kubernetes sprawl across multiple cloud providers. A single management console for administrators to use to manage clusters no matter where they reside, that will then translate your clicks into the proper API for that cloud provider, so you don’t have to learn any cloud specific commands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Day 2 General Session demos are focused around Tanzu as well, including the fictional company Tanzu Tees,  and you can also catch one of these session recordings from VMworld&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introducing VMware Tanzu Mission Control: Manage Kubernetes at Scale (KUB1835BU)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More Devs, No Problem: Managing Self-service Access with VMware Tanzu (KUB1851BU)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run Upstream Kubernetes Consistently Across Clouds with VMware Tanzu (KUB1840BU)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;kubernetes-academy&#34;&gt;Kubernetes Academy
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;No matter how VMware simplifies the tools needed to manage a Kubernetes cluster in production, it is still a fundamental change on how we look at applications. Which means training is still needed across IT to get everyone on the same page before architecting these next generation apps. Well VMware is determined to help here as well. Not only can you find several Hands-on-Labs on things like PKS, using NSX-T with Kubernetes, and we can assume Tanzu and Pacific after they release; but you can also take part in the new free training from Kubernetes Academy. At VMworld this year, I had an opportunity to sit through most of (busy schedule this year) an introduction  to containers and Kubernetes. Led by several employees of VMware that came over from the Heptio acquisition, they walked the group through the foundations and creating a container based web application and then combining it with a MySQL container in a Kubernetes cluster. Classes like these are what you will find at Kubernetes.Academy for free to help get everyone from development to infrastructure on the same page when it comes to tiny and mighty deployments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all the Kubernetes announcements and updates it is very clear, if learning your K8s isn’t on your roadmap, it should be.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>vRealize at VMworld US 2019</title>
        <link>https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/vrealize-at-vmworld-us-2019/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/vrealize-at-vmworld-us-2019/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It is that time of year again, with each VMworld we get new announcements for the vRealize Suite Cloud Management tools. This year, there is a common thread across most of them, supporting more Public Clouds and Kubernetes support, but if you listed to this year’s keynote that will likely not come as a surprise. We are also getting some pretty big updates in a few of the products as well, especially in the area of vRealize Automation.  I have tried to break down a summary for each product for now and hope to dive deeper into each as we get more information close to the time they get GA’d.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;vrealize-operations-80&#34;&gt;vRealize Operations 8.0
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I shared in my last post, vROPS 8.0 was announced bringing in many additional features, mostly focused on VMware’s goal to support the “any clod” part of its “Any App, Any Cloud, Any Device” vision.  For more details you can read my announcement post here:  &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.intelligencemodifier.com/blog/2019/8/19/announcing-vrealize-operations-80&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.intelligencemodifier.com/blog/2019/8/19/announcing-vrealize-operations-80&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;vrealize-automation-80&#34;&gt;vRealize Automation 8.0
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;entirely-new-appliance-architecture&#34;&gt;Entirely New Appliance Architecture
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It has been a long time rumored but vRA 8 finally contains the overhaul to application architecture. Each appliance will now be a self-contained Kubernetes Pod in which each function of vRA will run in its own group of containers. Sitting through the “Evolving vRealize Automation (HBO1323BU)” session at VMworld, its sounds like the “typical enterprise deployment” is planned to be 3 appliances, that’s it. In order to handle more workflows, you just give more resources to each Virtual Appliance, and the resources will get spread out as needed to the worker groups. This also means, NO MORE WINDOWS BASED IaaS SERVERS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/vrealize-at-vmworld-us-2019/vra8_arch.png&#34;
	width=&#34;750&#34;
	height=&#34;374&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/vrealize-at-vmworld-us-2019/vra8_arch_hu0a7e7fbb2353ea2476b65d8bfaca9ede_138530_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/vrealize-at-vmworld-us-2019/vra8_arch_hu0a7e7fbb2353ea2476b65d8bfaca9ede_138530_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34; &#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;200&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;481px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;application-overhaul&#34;&gt;Application Overhaul
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you have been using vRA for some time, get ready for some big changes. With 8.0 we will finally see all the new features and functionality beamed down from the vRealize Automation Cloud (formally CAS) product into our local data centers. Some of the big changes are&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fully New HTML 5 interface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to edit the YAML behind a blueprint right in the editing canvas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to version control your blueprints&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Action Based Extensibility (ABX) - node.js or Python scripts that can be used expand your workflows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vIDM services will be handled by an external Workspace ONE Access appliance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And so much more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one personally has me really excited and I cannot wait to get my hands on the GA’d bits to start working with it.  In the meantime, if you are curious on what this version be like, you can check out the Hands-on Lab HOL-2002-03-CMP which is a Getting Started lab for vRealize Automation Cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;vrealize-suite-life-cycle-manager-80&#34;&gt;vRealize Suite Life-cycle Manager 8.0
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next up, jumping from version 2.1 to 8.0 we shouldn’t be surprised that vRSLCM has also gotten quite the re-work again. While details are still a bit sparse, we do know that the UI is getting another large overhaul. There will also be an area of the UI referred to as the “Locker”, which seems to be where you will manage passwords, certificates and licenses according to early screenshots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, vRSLCM will no longer be an optional part of your management cluster. Right now, it is being listed as the only way to deploy vRealize Automation 8.0. It is also looking to be what might be the suggested method to deploy the Workspace ONE Access appliance that will act as authentication point for all the new vRealize Suite tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;vrealize-network-insight-50&#34;&gt;vRealize Network Insight 5.0
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the 5.0 release there seems to be 3 main new features being added.  First VMware is adding Support for  NSX SD-WAN (VeloCould).  In demo’s I have seen, this allows your team to have visibility into Flows and Application health for traffic flowing between your VeloCoud sites. Next, they are adding native Kubernetes support. Allowing you to see the traffic in and out of your clusters and even down to the Pod and Service levels of each. Last but not least, in their ever forward moving push to support “Any Cloud” vRNI will now support Azure networks in the same way it already supports AWS and VMware Cloud on AWS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;product-name-alignment&#34;&gt;Product Name Alignment
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, it’s the small things that make a large difference. As part of the slew of new vRealize goodness, VMware announced a alignment of product naming between their SaaS offerings and the more traditional “on-prem” offerings!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cloud Automation  Services (CAS) is now vRealize Automation Cloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Log Intelligence is now vRealize Log Insight Cloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Network Insight is now vRealize Network Insight Cloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They also announced the upcoming vRealize Operations Cloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/vrealize-at-vmworld-us-2019/vRCloud.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1000&#34;
	height=&#34;411&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/vrealize-at-vmworld-us-2019/vRCloud_hu217cd74b485aa1dac7df33b65afda68b_97941_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/vrealize-at-vmworld-us-2019/vRCloud_hu217cd74b485aa1dac7df33b65afda68b_97941_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34; &#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;243&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;583px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Announcing vRealize Operations 8.0</title>
        <link>https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/vrops8-annouced/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/vrops8-annouced/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today during VMworld 2019, the next version of vRealize Operations Manager was announced.  Version 8.0 focuses on improving many existing features and adding several new features especially in the area of Hybrid and Multi Cloud support. Here are some highlights of the new features you can expect when vRealize Operations Manager 8.0 drops later this year&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;core-platform-updates&#34;&gt;Core Platform Updates
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More powerful Self-Driving operations leveraging Machine Learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More What-If Analysis Scenarios including Hyper Converged Infrastructure and Data-center Comparison&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Troubleshooting Workbench – Correlate information in one dashboard to help track down root cause of issues. You can even have multiple Troubleshooting Workbenches setup at once to help on multiple issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continuous Availability Custer Mode – Spreading your vRealize Operations Nodes across multiple sites/fault domains to help assure cluster availability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;updated-costing-tools&#34;&gt;Updated Costing Tools
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Starting with version 6.7 VMware has started implementing cost analysis into the vROPS platform. Now with 8.0, they are adding many improvements and bringing vROPS closer (if not at) feature parity with the vRealize Business for Cloud offering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integration with vRealize Automation  - vROPS will now be able to provide Day 0 and Day 2 costing  information as part of vRealize Automation workflows.  Previously only some of this information could be obtained via vRBC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to customize costs per data-center.  VMware acknowledges that not all your data-centers cost the same to run. So starting in 8.0 you will be able to enter custom costing for each data-center connected to vROPS if needed .&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Depreciation Metrics – You can now take into account for Depreciation of value for hardware over the span of its life in your environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;multi-cloud-support&#34;&gt;Multi-Cloud Support
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New Management Packs for Cloud Services
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Azure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VMware CloudHealth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Costing Management Pack for VMware Cloud on AWS – pull in your costing data from you VMCoAWS portal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for Day 2 workload optimization within VMware Cloud on AWS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;application-monitoring&#34;&gt;Application Monitoring
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;20 new applications and services available to monitor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inclusion of Custom Script monitoring&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;service-discovery-management-pack-now-part-core-product&#34;&gt;Service Discovery Management Pack now part core product
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connects to Guest VM via VMWare Tools agent (version 10.2 or higher)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Still requires Guest OS credentials to access&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8.0 will ship with 41 known services out of box&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to add new services to monitoring white list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No extra agent needed for one-time script execution such as ‘Get Top-N services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;additional-compliance-related-features&#34;&gt;Additional Compliance Related Features
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New Compliance Rules and workflows Out of Box, including support for VMware Cloud on AWS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ability to Import and Export custom compliance standards&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VMware Announcement: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://blogs.vmware.com/management/2019/08/whats-new-in-vrealize-operations-8-0.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://blogs.vmware.com/management/2019/08/whats-new-in-vrealize-operations-8-0.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Preparing for VMworld 2019</title>
        <link>https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/preparing-for-vmworld2019/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/preparing-for-vmworld2019/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I am very excited and honored to be selected to attend VMworld 2019 in San Francisco via the vExpert Blogger Pass. This will be my second VMworld, the first being in Vegas during 2017. So now that my travel plan is locked in, and I am scrolling through sessions to attend I wanted to look back at how I am planning my 2nd venture to this convention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;keynotes&#34;&gt;Keynotes
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am of course planning to attend the Monday and Tuesday keynotes (at the time of writing I don’t see a end of conference keynote listed in the schedule). Now I also went to these in 2017, however… I now know the secret of the VMvillage bean bag chairs which would be my recommendation for viewing. Just kickback after breakfast and watch in much less crowded comfort, if you get there early enough to grab a seat that is. (and if this is still a thing this year)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sessions&#34;&gt;Sessions
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2017, I was still pretty new to the role of System Administrator, and that was also the first time attending an IT conference. This coupled with not knowing many other people going, I loaded my calendar from beginning to end with sessions. Now, this isn’t really a mistake. Most of the sessions I attended had something to do with something I was either doing at work or needed to learn. However, going into this year I am trying to keep some time open to spend time with my co-workers going for the first time, Visit the Expo Hall, stop by the Ask the Expert area and spend some time on my next point…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;interacting-with-the-vcommunity&#34;&gt;Interacting with the vCommunity
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is probably going to be my biggest difference from attending in 2017. I wouldn’t say i was very active in the VMware community 2 years ago. I attended VMUGs and followed some people on Twitter. However, I didn’t really reach out past current and past co-workers. For anyone I followed on Twitter I didn’t know, my level of interaction was probably a ‘like’ at most. One of the people i knew that also went tried his best to introduce me to as many people in person as possible but I was mostly a deer in the headlights the entire time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward 2 years. I am in my 2nd year as a vExpert and made the cut for the first year of the Cloud Management Subprogram this year to boot. I interact with a much larger group of vCommunity people over Twitter and the vExpert Slack, and even take place in discussions (somewhat). Offline, I have continued to attend VMUG meetings locally where I have gotten to know more members and the leaders. Just 2 weeks ago, I was part of a group from our local VMUG chapter that hit the road to attend the Indianapolis VMUG UserCon. Here I got to meet quite a few people I have been following for a while on Twitter and met several new people that I have added to my follow list. The largest difference personally, would probably be that I cracked into the world of speaking this year. I presented at my local VMUG for the first time and now I am scheduled to give a talk at a neighboring VMUGs UserCon this September.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, going into VMworld this year, I plan to leave time open to catch up with people i know, and meet new people. I have also signed up/or plan to take place in a few vCommunity events like the vCoffee exchange. I will of course spend some time in the Bloggers area trying to put together a few posts during the event. If you see a guy clearing his screen for the 5th time to start again, that is probably me. Stop and say Hi!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, yes, I have registered for a few of the after-hours parties :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second Also, wear comfortable walking shoes. Sandals were a bad choice last time&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_Eric&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>VMWorld 2018 - vRealize Suite Announcements</title>
        <link>https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/vmworld2018-vrealize-suite-announcements/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/vmworld2018-vrealize-suite-announcements/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to make it VMWorld this year, but I spent a good part of the day pouring over twitter and blog posts to find information on the 2018 version of the vRealize Suite. Below are just some quick notes on the features i am most excited about or found the most interesting, along with the official VMware blog post link to learn  more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;vrealize-automation---75-also-vrealize-business-for-cloud-75&#34;&gt;vRealize Automation - 7.5 (also vRealize Business for Cloud 7.5)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clarity UI has finally come (officially) to vRA. Taking one more step to unifying the user experience across the suite and VMware products overall.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NSX-T Support, making NSX-T blueprints as easy as NSX-V has been.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beefing up the &amp;lsquo;Containers&amp;rsquo; tab with official support for VMware Pivotal Container Services (PKS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for VMware Cloud on AWS
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://blogs.VMware.com/management/2018/08/whats-new-vrealize-automation-7-5.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://blogs.VMware.com/management/2018/08/whats-new-vrealize-automation-7-5.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;vrealize-operations-manager---70&#34;&gt;vRealize Operations Manager - 7.0
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New and simplified dashboard creation and sharing. This includes a feature i have been waiting for since vCOPS, being able to have dashboards shared out as URLs that DO NOT require a login.  Finally a NOC style dashboard that you don&amp;rsquo;t need to manually log into on your NOC displays.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Several VMware Cloud on AWS enhancements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lots of fine tuning and finishing features that were added/overhauled in 6.7
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://blogs.VMware.com/management/2018/08/whats-new-in-vrealize-operations-7-0.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://blogs.VMware.com/management/2018/08/whats-new-in-vrealize-operations-7-0.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;vrealize-loginsight---47&#34;&gt;vRealize LogInsight - 4.7
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not as exciting of a release (based on information i can find so far) as the other vRealize products. The official blog post lists server REST API improvements including being able to read certificate information via REST, Change to vCenter Integration, and various UI improvements and bug fixes.
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://blogs.VMware.com/management/2018/08/vrealize-log-insight-4-7-september-2018-new-release.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://blogs.VMware.com/management/2018/08/vrealize-log-insight-4-7-september-2018-new-release.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;vrealize--lifecycle-configuration-manager---20&#34;&gt;vRealize  Lifecycle Configuration Manager - 2.0
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;So far this is only referenced in the overall vRealize Suite 2018 post (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://blogs.VMware.com/management/2018/08/whats-new-vrealize-suite-2018.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://blogs.VMware.com/management/2018/08/whats-new-vrealize-suite-2018.html&lt;/a&gt;), however the drastic improvements from 1.0 to 1.3 have my very excited to see what has caused the jump up to 2.0 all of a sudden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;vrealize-network-insight---39&#34;&gt;vRealize Network Insight - 3.9
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not a lot of new information was provided yet, but i will try to update this post if more comes out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://blogs.VMware.com/management/2018/08/VMware-vrealize-network-insight-3-9.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://blogs.VMware.com/management/2018/08/VMware-vrealize-network-insight-3-9.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Replacing a vRealize LogInsight node</title>
        <link>https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/replaceing-vrli-node/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/replaceing-vrli-node/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;NOTE: I am not a member of VMware Global Support Services, nor should you use this as any sort of replacement for a service ticket or vmWare published documentation.  This is just a process that I had to piece together during my own support case with them wanted to document for home lab use. Attempt the below steps at your own risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;problem-statement&#34;&gt;Problem Statement
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;While trying to expand storage per the VMware documentation within 2 separate vRLI 4.5 clusters, I had 1 of 3 nodes in each cluster fail to expand storage.  After a few hours with support via email and phone, and several attempts to salvage the nodes by trying to expand the storage manually, it was decided that the nodes needed to be replaced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tldr&#34;&gt;TLDR
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unjoin bad node from cluster, backup the log data off the node, Delete node, build new node, join new node, restore data to appliance, load data into vRLI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;procedure-used&#34;&gt;Procedure Used
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove Node from cluster via UI by following the documentation for your version of vRLI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find a secondary location you can temporarily store the data. I had a utility server that i added an extra 2.3 TB drive to for this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We used PSFTP to connect and move data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;login to the &amp;lsquo;bad&amp;rsquo; node as root  &lt;code&gt;open root@&amp;lt;applianceFQDN&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;use &lt;code&gt;lcd &amp;lt;destionation loc&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; to set your local directory to the destination for the data you found in step 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;navigate to the log &amp;lsquo;blob&amp;rsquo; on the appliance - &lt;code&gt;cd /storage/core/loginsight/cidata&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pull that data - &lt;code&gt;get -r store store&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wait. this is probably going to take a while. I had to leave hours  running overnight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When the file copy is done, validate you have the right amount in your backup location&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had our first copy fail to copy it all so I had to try again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Power down the node being replaced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delete the VM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redeploy a new node with the same host-name and IP address&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join the new node&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;via the vRLI console, place the new node into Maintenance Mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open PSFTP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;login to the new node as root  &lt;code&gt;open root@&amp;lt;applianceFQDN&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;lcd&lt;/code&gt; back to your location for step 2. DO NOT lcd INTO the &amp;lsquo;store&amp;rsquo; folder that was created&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd /storage/core/loginsight/cidata&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;load the data back into the appliance using &lt;code&gt;put -r store store&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Waiting again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Putty into the appliance as root&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;run &lt;code&gt;cd /storage/core/loginsight/cidata&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set the correct permission son the store folder with &lt;code&gt;chmod 755 store&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stop services on the node with &lt;code&gt;service LogInsight stop&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;run the following script to load the log data into the LogInsight application: &lt;code&gt;for bucket in $(ls /storage/core/loginsight/cidata/store | grep -v &#39;generation\|buckets\|strata_write.lock&#39;); do echo y | /usr/lib/loginsight/application/sbin/bucket-index add $bucket --statuses archived; done&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;more waiting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;start up services - &lt;code&gt;service loginsight start&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;via the vRLI UI, bring the cluster out of maintenance mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The New ISE - Visual Studio Code</title>
        <link>https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/new-ise-visualstudiocode/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/new-ise-visualstudiocode/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Back around late 2013 when i started looking at PowerShell, I was a Help Desk agent and just looking to save some time on calls, maybe a faster way to look up user accounts then the hardly ever improved Active Directory Users and Computers UI. Soon however, with ample help from co-workers, I started to look at using scripting to improve our imaging process for laptops/desktops. To remove manual steps that just wasted our time.  This meant i needed a new tool, I needed to be ale setup logic flows with IF/ELSE or read in parameters such as Service Tag number among other things.  So started my journey to find a Power Shell script editor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The choice of which script editor to use is never easy when your starting your journey to learn PowerShell. Every PowerShell user that has come before you has their favorite and probably at least one they feel is equivalent to a dumpster fire. Eventually however you make a choice, because you get beyond running single commands in a standard PS shell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time, from what i remember, the 2 main choices among my coworkers were the native PowerShell ISE that comes with the Windows OS and PowerGUI (which as of writing this seems to have been lost in the spin-off Dell performed of the QUEST software in 2016). The ISE is a great starting point, it is already installed if you have PowerShell, there is very little setup needed and it just works. PowerGUI had a few nice features, like a debugging mode that I personally was never ever able to replicate inside the ISE that allowed me to step through my script and see how variables fill in to help spot logic issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From 2014 until probably early this year mostly stuck to the ISE. As much as I enjoyed some features of PowerGUI it was very slow loading, and Dell seemed more than happy to let it die on the vine, never providing updates. I had a quick fling with PowerShell Studio, while i was designing a wrapper for the Microsoft User State Migration Tool, for my last job and in my current role i haven&amp;rsquo;t had a need for a UI designer for PowerShell. However, there was a new challenger approaching, and it was going to change a lot of what I wanted from my scripting editor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;enter-visual-studio-code-by-the-new-microsoft&#34;&gt;Enter Visual Studio Code by the &amp;ldquo;new&amp;rdquo; Microsoft
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In early 2016, Microsoft release .Net Core. An free to use, open-source, cross-platform  version of the .Net framework that had for so long been a Windows only thing. A few months later the next open-source project dropped from Microsoft, Visual Studio Code.  With this, Microsoft was taking the core script editor from a product they get ALOT of money for and making it another free, open-source, cross-platform  product. I downloaded one of the earlier builds and saw potential, but between my skill-set at the time and how green the product was I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t make the jump and sacrifice the speed and ease i could work with ISE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I continued to use the ISE, and it turned out the team behind VSC were working very hard at refining this new tool of theirs. In late November-December 2016 VSC came up again at work. I don&amp;rsquo;t really remember how, but upon looking into it again we found that it had changed quite a bit i some wonderful ways. The user experience had been improved,  An array of plugins were available to bring things like Intellisense, and other beloved tools from the ISE over to this new editor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It didn&amp;rsquo;t happen right away, but VSC has now all but replaced ISE in our team (for the most part). I think it quickly showed its true strength, not being a piece of the Operating System.  The ISE is still very strong, mainly because as a Windows server admin, i would be hard pressed to login to a system without the ISE right there. Which if i need to tweak a script quick that lives on a service for a scheduled task is awesome.  However, because of how it was integrated at the OS level you would rarely, if ever get updates for it.  Visual Studio Code being a separate application, and being so open meant that in the year that I have been using it, features have been rolling in month by month (faster if you are part of the Insiders build ring from Microsoft).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several of the &amp;ldquo;must install&amp;rdquo; plugins from when I started using it simply don&amp;rsquo;t exist any more, because the VSC team baked those very helpful features into the program. The native Git support (after installing the Git framework separately) allowed our team to quickly move into have a code repository. For those less familiar with PowerShell, Intellisense is baked in, and it also has PSScriptAnalyzer, a best practices analyzer, built in as well which means this editor can help you learn. The best part being that the number of settings you can tweak throughout and the frequent updates and vast add-on library this editor evolves with you as your skills increase. You can even set your space vs tab preference or decide if your starting curly bracket &amp;ldquo;{&amp;rdquo; goes on the current line you are one or on a new line&amp;hellip; but those are wars for another day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its not perfect, but it improves with every build (well except for the whole icon color issue of October 2017: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://code.visualstudio.com/blogs/2017/10/24/theicon&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://code.visualstudio.com/blogs/2017/10/24/theicon&lt;/a&gt;) and I think its worth giving a shot no matter what skill level you are at with PowerShell or some other scripting language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visual Studio Code on GitHub: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/Microsoft/vscode&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://github.com/Microsoft/vscode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft product page and download links: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://code.visualstudio.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://code.visualstudio.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*&lt;em&gt;Release Dates are based of the product&amp;rsquo;s Wikipedia entries or other Google-Fu, i apologize if they are not 100% accurate&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Connect-VIServer -Part 1</title>
        <link>https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/connect-viserver-part-1/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/connect-viserver-part-1/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;installing-and-connecting&#34;&gt;Installing and Connecting
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before we get to far,you will need to have PowerCLI installed.  You can probably get away with a an older version but as of my writing this I have only validated these commands using PowerShell 5.1 and PowerCLI 6.5.x&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;prerequisites&#34;&gt;Prerequisites
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic knowledge of PowerShell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uninstall any versions older than 6.5 from the Windows Control Panel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update PowerShell (WMF) 5.1 - Info Here&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If this is your first time installing anything via Find-Module and Install-Module, you will most likely be prompted to install the Nuget module when you run the commands for the first time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;installing-powercli-from-the-psgallery&#34;&gt;Installing PowerCLI from the PSGallery
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Starting with version 6.5, VMware has stopped delivering PowerCLI via MSI installer. They have instead embraced the more standard delivery of PowerShell Modules via Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s PSGallery. This has the benefits of making the module easier to install on new computers, and easier to update when a new version is released. Also by using a more standard setup for the module, this means you no longer have to launch a special PowerCLI shell. The PowerCLI module is loaded right into the normal PowerShell window making thinks like scripts much less complicated. For users of previous versions, as mentioned above in the prerequisites, need to manually uninstall all old version as the new Install method is not capable of doing this. Now lets get installing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open a PowerShell prompt in Administrator Mode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the following command to Find PowerCLI out on PSGallery
&lt;code&gt;Find-Module -Name vmware.powercli&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You should have a result like the one below:
&lt;img src=&#34;https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/connect-viserver-part-1/Find-Module.png&#34;
	width=&#34;839&#34;
	height=&#34;58&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/connect-viserver-part-1/Find-Module_hu1d7b9c62c4342cf54269af3c3f04e766_2319_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/connect-viserver-part-1/Find-Module_hu1d7b9c62c4342cf54269af3c3f04e766_2319_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34; &#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;1446&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;3471px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now to install the module use the following command, which will then ask you to confirm you want to install the module from an &amp;ldquo;Untrusted Repository&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Find-Module -Name vmware.powercli | Install-Module -AllowClobber&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/connect-viserver-part-1/Confirm&amp;#43;Install.png&#34;
	width=&#34;807&#34;
	height=&#34;73&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/connect-viserver-part-1/Confirm&amp;#43;Install_hu587614982567aa3f7f812132e0b8c23d_4963_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/connect-viserver-part-1/Confirm&amp;#43;Install_hu587614982567aa3f7f812132e0b8c23d_4963_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34; &#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;1105&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;2653px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will now see PowerShell download and install PowerCL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/connect-viserver-part-1/Installing.png&#34;
	width=&#34;750&#34;
	height=&#34;90&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/connect-viserver-part-1/Installing_huf66ce9745625c2c64dd3d8e5879cce2f_29255_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/connect-viserver-part-1/Installing_huf66ce9745625c2c64dd3d8e5879cce2f_29255_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34; &#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;833&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;2000px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the progress bars disappear, you are now ready to connect to your VMware environment via PowerCLI! Which I will cover in part 2.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Set-Location &#39;VMworld 2017&#39;</title>
        <link>https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/set-location-vmworld2017/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://intelligencemodifier.com/p/set-location-vmworld2017/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Well technically I am now back home, but I liked the title and ran with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, I was lucky enough to attend my first VMWorld in Las Vegas, NV. To say that it was awesome, would be an understatement. Not only did I have a chance listen to some amazing sessions (and ear mark several for viewing once the VoDs are up), but I also got to meet quite a few VMware Community members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was sent to VMWorld for my job, which is something i am very grateful for, and I wanted to make sure my manager didn&amp;rsquo;t regret sending me to Las Vegas for almost a week on the company&amp;rsquo;s dime.  So I made sure to register and attend as many expert led sessions as possible on topics that relate to my day to day job and items that may prove beneficial to our shop in the future. They ranged from Introductory Overviews of new solutions to Technical Deep Dives of items I am responsible for on a daily basis. There were even a few community discussion groups that weren&amp;rsquo;t on a strict topic, but more just Q&amp;amp;A between peers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I got to badge pickup I knew that this cannot be the only VMWorld I attend. I met peers on the airplane and talked about differences and similarities between our IT lives.  Walking the halls towards registration it became obvious that there was something unique about being together with 20-30 thousand of one&amp;rsquo;s peers.  Meeting people from across the globe, that deal with or have found solutions to issues you face every day was amazing. There was even a point near the end of the week in the VMware Technical Network (VMTN) booth where a speaker on the VMware Validated Designs had dropped out due to illness where I found my self sharing my, all be it still limited, knowledge about the VVDs and why one might choose to follow them. Thanks to a friend, and former co-worker, I was also able to meet several of the people behind the blogs and Twitter handles that I follow; Along with new individuals that will be added to that list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was surprised at how much one could benefit from the &amp;ldquo;Vendor Showcase&amp;rdquo; as well. Typically these setups are known for trading E-Mail address for S.W.A.G, and don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, that did happen. Meeting new companies, either within new spaces that I haven&amp;rsquo;t dealt with yet, or alternatives to solutions I already help maintain.  However, the biggest surprise was that I was also able connect with vendors I already deal with through work, and because they sent actual experts to attend the booth I got quick answers to some questions that I have had for a while that support calls for forum posts never fully answered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, of course, there were the vendor sponsored events that started after the conference doors closed each night. Being my first VMWorld and my first major IT conference in general, I am not sure anything could have prepared me for the scope of these. From networking social hours to flat out concerts, these companies get that we IT work hard and like to play harder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you VMWorld I will never forget my first trip, and now I must figure out how to get back next year&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$Eric&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
