<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Powershell on Intellegence Modifer</title>
    <link>https://intelligencemodifier.com/tags/powershell/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Powershell on Intellegence Modifer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://intelligencemodifier.com/tags/powershell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The New ISE - Visual Studio Code</title>
      <link>https://intelligencemodifier.com/post/2017-vscode-ise/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://intelligencemodifier.com/post/2017-vscode-ise/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Back around late 2013 when i started looking at PowerShell, I was a Help Desk agent and just looking to save some time on calls, maybe a faster way to look up user accounts then the hardly ever improved Active Directory Users and Computers UI. Soon however, with ample help from co-workers, I started to look at using scripting to improve our imaging process for laptops/desktops. To remove manual steps that just wasted our time.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connect-VIServer -Part 1</title>
      <link>https://intelligencemodifier.com/post/2017-powercli-pt1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://intelligencemodifier.com/post/2017-powercli-pt1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Installing and Connecting Before we get to far,you will need to have PowerCLI installed. You can probably get away with a an older version but as of my writing this I have only validated these commands using PowerShell 5.1 and PowerCLI 6.5.x
Prerequisites Basic knowledge of PowerShell Uninstall any versions older than 6.5 from the Windows Control Panel Update PowerShell (WMF) 5.1 - Info Here If this is your first time installing anything via Find-Module and Install-Module, you will most likely be prompted to install the Nuget module when you run the commands for the first time.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
